Quentin McRee

Web Developer qmcree@gmail.com qmcree.com (512) 588-3394 Austin, TX

Summary

Passionate, driven, and successful developer with several years of experience in the some of the most popular languages, environments, and practices.

Skills & Expertise

PHP, JavaScript, Drupal, CSS3, jQuery, HTML 5, SQL, JSON, Apache, AJAX, MVC, XML, Web Applications, Databases, Programming, Linux, Git, MySQL, OOP, Database Design, Web Services, REST, Laravel, Yii, FogBugz, PhpStorm

Experience

Senior PHP / MySQL Developer at Adscend Media July 2014 - Present

Web Developer at Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

October 2012 - June 2014

- Analyze business objectives, create specifications, and develop solutions for desired functionality on Web applications, Web sites and other traditional technologies
- Develop and integrate database-driven Web sites and applications from provided design wireframes to complete functionality
- Develop new technologies in PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, and other languages
- Ensure timely completion of all deliverables
- Analyze business requirements to determine project specifications
- Work collaboratively in a team environment with the Web team and other developers to enhance the user experience and to identify and implement methods to enrich the development process

- Participate in all phases of software development lifecycle, from analysis and discovery, through release and beyond
- Maintain working knowledge of current Web technologies and best practices through continuing education, professional conferences, workshops, and online resources

Web Developer at Freelance

January 2004 - June 2014 (10 years, 6 months)

- Developed and commercialized internal staff messaging Web application built on LAMP stack. Routinely provided application support to licensees and deployed updates containing enhancements and fixes.
- Developed Web sites using Drupal CMS for several clients, including non-profit organizations, a law practice, an oil and gas company, and an audio/visual company.

IT Support Specialist at Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

June 2012 - October 2012 (5 months)

Family Room Specialist at Apple

June 2011 - March 2012 (10 months)

Genius Bar

IT Specialist at Digital Systems, Inc.

December 2007 - June 2011 (3 years, 7 months)

Education

Tulane University

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Applied Computing Systems and Technology

2011 - 2016 (expected)

3.8 GPA

Golden Key International Honour Society

Mississippi College

Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Computer Science

2011 - 2011